export const BIOLOGYA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The cell as the basic unit of life consists of",
A: "cell wall and vacuole",
B: "nucleus and cell wall",
C: "cytoplasm and nucleus",
D: "cytoplasm and vacuole",
answer: "C. cytoplasm and nucleus",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which members of the classes live mainly in an aquatic habitat?",
A: "I",
B: "II",
C: "III",
D: "IV",
answer: "A. I",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the classes is characterised by the possession of two pairs of antennae?",
A: "I",
B: "II",
C: "III",
D: "IV",
answer: "A. I",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The organism with spiral chloroplasts and nucleus suspended by cytoplasmic strands is",
A: "Volvox",
B: "Spirogyra",
C: "Paramecium",
D: "Euglena",
answer: "B. Spirogyra",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The network of double membrane that conveys materials through the cytoplasm is the",
A: "plasma membrane",
B: "nuclear membrane",
C: "mitochondrion",
D: "endoplasmic reticulum",
answer: "D. endoplasmic reticulum",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Food is stored in the part labeled",
A: "I",
B: "II",
C: "III",
D: "IV",
answer: "B. II",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The plant is a",
A: "stem tuber",
B: "bulb",
C: "stolon",
D: "runner",
answer: "B. bulb",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The part labeled I is the",
A: "apical bud",
B: "scale leaf",
C: "adventitious root",
D: "fleshy leaf",
answer: "B. scale leaf",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following materials is not a living semi-permeable membrane?",
A: "pig's bladder",
B: "Unripe pawpaw fruit",
C: "Yam tuber",
D: "Sheet of cellophane",
answer: "D. Sheet of cellophane",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. In an experiment, mould and yeast cells were transferred into an environment with low oxygen concentration. After a few days, the mould dies while the yeast cells did not. Which of the following statements best explains the following observation.",
A: "The yeast cells carried out photosynthesis while the mould did not",
B: "Photosynthesis does not take place in the absence of oxygen",
C: "Respiration can take place in yeast cells in the absence of oxygen",
D: "Respiration does not occur in the mould",
answer: "C. Respiration can take place in yeast cells in the absence of oxygen",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following tissues does not provide support in flowering plants?",
A: "Collenchyma",
B: "Parenchyma",
C: "Xylem",
D: "Phloem",
answer: "B. Parenchyma",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The set-up directly measure",
A: "transpiration of water by the shoot",
B: "evaporation of water from the leaves",
C: "absorption of water by the shoot",
D: "loss of mineral salts from the leaves",
answer: "A. transpiration of water by the shoot",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The set-up can measure comparatively the rate of",
A: "evaporation from leaves on a single shoot under different experimental conditions",
B: "salt uptake by shoots from different plants",
C: "transpiration of a single shoot of a plant under different experimental conditions",
D: "water uptake by roots of different plants",
answer: "C. transpiration of a single shoot of a plant under different experimental conditions",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The respiratory organ of a cockroach",
A: "air sac",
B: "trachea",
C: "lung book",
D: "lung",
answer: "B. trachea",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The excretory product of some reptiles, birds and insects is",
A: "urea",
B: "urine",
C: "ammonia",
D: "uric acid",
answer: "D. uric acid",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The part of the mammalian kidney that stores urine is the",
A: "capsule",
B: "medulla",
C: "pelvis",
D: "bladder",
answer: "D. bladder",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The properties of endocrine system include the following except",
A: "secretion of hormones",
B: "transportation by blood to target organ",
C: "having specific effect",
D: "release of secretion into ducts",
answer: "D. release of secretion into ducts",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The part of the central nervous system that controls unconscious actions in humans is the",
A: "cerebellum",
B: "cerebrum",
C: "spinal cord",
D: "optic nerves",
answer: "A. cerebellum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. What happens when the ciliary muscles of the eye contract? The",
A: "lens become more concave",
B: "lens become more convex",
C: "lens gets a longer focal length",
D: "suspensory ligament becomes tight",
answer: "C. lens gets a longer focal length",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The function of the part labeled I is",
A: "receiving the pollen grain",
B: "passage for the male gamete to the ovary",
C: "germination of the pollen grain",
D: "site for double fertilization in the plant",
answer: "B. passage for the male gamete to the ovary",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The part labeled II is the",
A: "unfused stigma",
B: "fused style",
C: "fused ovaries",
D: "unfused anther",
answer: "C. fused ovaries",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The reagent used in testing for carbon (IV) oxide is",
A: "copper sulphate solution",
B: "lime water",
C: "hydrochloric acid",
D: "sodium hydroxide solution",
answer: "B. lime water",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Oxygen comes out of the stomata during photosynthesis through the process known as",
A: "diffusion",
B: "transpiration pull",
C: "osmosis",
D: "active transport",
answer: "A. diffusion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The first stable product of photosynthesis is",
A: "starch",
B: "fructose",
C: "glucose",
D: "sucrose",
answer: "C. glucose",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. An example of a trace elements is",
A: "potassium",
B: "calcium",
C: "magnesium",
D: "copper",
answer: "D. copper",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following statements about a mixture of a protein-digesting enzyme and starch solution would be correct? The protein-digesting enzyme",
A: "has no effect on the starch solution",
B: "leads to the production of amino acids",
C: "leads to the production of glucose",
D: "digest the starch",
answer: "A. has no effect on the starch solution",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The mutualism type of relationship is different from a parasitic relationship because in mutualism",
A: "both organisms involved benefit",
B: "none of the organisms benefits or harm each other",
C: "both organisms harm each other",
D: "only one of the organisms is harmed",
answer: "A. both organisms involved benefit",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. What type of habitat is W?",
A: "Rainforest",
B: "Pond",
C: "Desert",
D: "Ocean",
answer: "B. Pond",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following statements about habitat W is correct? The",
A: "absence of lions and antelopes shows that the habitat is terrestrial",
B: "presence of Tilapia and planktons shows that the habitat is not aquatic",
C: "type of organisms present indicate that habitat is aquatic",
D: "absence of grasses indicates that the habitat is terrestrial",
answer: "C. type of organisms present indicate that habitat is aquatic",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The number of lions and antelops in habitat Y shows that the lion",
A: "is the prey while the antelope is the predator",
B: "is the predator while the antelope is the prey",
C: "and the antelope are preys to each other",
D: "and the antelopes are predators",
answer: "B. is the predator while the antelope is the prey",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A disadvantage of the abiotic factor measured by the instrument is that it",
A: "is an agent of pollination",
B: "is necessary for germination",
C: "leads to flooding when in excess",
D: "is used for irrigation",
answer: "C. leads to flooding when in excess",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. When the instrument is in use, it is usually",
A: "placed slightly above soil level",
B: "placed on a table",
C: "suspended in air",
D: "suspended to moving water",
answer: "A. placed slightly above soil level",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Soil with the finest texture is",
A: "silt",
B: "clay",
C: "sand",
D: "gravel",
answer: "A. silt",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The position occupied by an organism in food chain is the",
A: "energy level",
B: "niche",
C: "trophic level",
D: "biomass",
answer: "C. trophic level",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The depletion of the ozone layer will result in the earth surface receiving more",
A: "gamma rays",
B: "infra-red rays",
C: "ultraviolet rays",
D: "X-rays",
answer: "C. ultraviolet rays",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The insects whose activities are both beneficial and harmful to humans are;",
A: "I and II",
B: "II and III",
C: "II and IV",
D: "III and IV",
answer: "B. II and IV",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the insects destroys grains?",
A: "I",
B: "II",
C: "III",
D: "IV",
answer: "D. IV",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Conservation of natural resources does not",
A: "maintain a balanced ecosystem",
B: "preserve the beauty of nature",
C: "attract tourists",
D: "threaten the survival of species",
answer: "D. threaten the survival of species",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A company was prohibited from producing bags made from natural leopard skin. This is an attempt to conserve",
A: "land",
B: "water",
C: "wildlife",
D: "minerals",
answer: "C. wildlife",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following substances is not a conservable natural resource?",
A: "Mineral",
B: "Air",
C: "Soil",
D: "Water",
answer: "A. Mineral",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A child that can receive blood donation from anybody belongs to the blood group",
A: "O",
B: "A",
C: "B",
D: "AB",
answer: "D. AB",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Variation which exhibits a wide range from one extreme to the other is",
A: "phenotypic variation",
B: "discontinuous variation",
C: "continuous variation",
D: "genotypic variation",
answer: "C. continuous variation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Measurements of height and weight of students in a class show",
A: "discontinuous variation",
B: "continuous variation",
C: "shortness is more prevalent",
D: "fatness is less prevalent",
answer: "B. continuous variation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following statements about chromosomes is correct?",
A: "All the chromosomes of a species are the same shape",
B: "The number present in a specie is constant",
C: "They are neatly arranged in a cytoplasm",
D: "They bear ribosomes on their outer membranes",
answer: "B. The number present in a specie is constant",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following diseases can be inherited?",
A: "Pneumonia",
B: "Whooping cough",
C: "Sickle cell anemia",
D: "Malaria",
answer: "C. Sickle cell anemia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. If the F1 generation are plants with high yield and resistance, the genotype of the F1 generation plants would be",
A: "YYRR",
B: "YyRr",
C: "yyRr",
D: "yyrr",
answer: "A. YYRR",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The process that gave rise to the F1 generation is",
A: "self fertilization",
B: "cross fertilization",
C: "out-breeding",
D: "test cross",
answer: "B. cross fertilization",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Replication of DNA molecules is catalysed by an enzyme called",
A: "polymerase",
B: "ptyalin",
C: "pepsin",
D: "amylase",
answer: "A. polymerase",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Who proposed the theory of evolution by natural selection?",
A: "Darwin",
B: "Lamark",
C: "Aristotle",
D: "Linnaeus",
answer: "A. Darwin",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following statements best explains the reason why termites swarm at night?",
A: "Light is not necessary for swarming",
B: "They avoid day-flying birds",
C: "Light destroys their wings",
D: "They can only see in the dark",
answer: "D. They can only see in the dark",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]